Finding Aid for the Synanon Foundation Records LSC.0342
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Subject Files
  - Finance: through Ledger books - cash disbursement & receipts -, 1966 October-December 1962. (Box 67)
  - Financial statement - through Weekly expenses - SM -, December 1963 1967-1969. (Box 68)
  - Expense account reports: through Fresno country board of supervisors., 1969-1970 (Box 69)
  - Game: articles through Graphics: logo. (Box 70)
  - Graphics: through Holidays: articles / cards., 1966-1972 (Box 71)
  - Holidays: music / cards through The hut (file added after, 1983). (Box 72)
  - Industries: through Lawsuits: Faucette case., 1966 (Box 73)
  - Bequests - legal through Legal: letters, 1961-1962. (Box 74)
  - John Ciampa - review file through Marks - Rodrigues report. (Box 75)
  - Meanderings of a dog robber through Nature of activities. (Box 76)
  - Out card (Nevada ) through New York - correspondence., 1962 1972 (Box 77)
  - No smoking through Athens investors party. (Box 78)
  - Former Athens members through Olympics - Santa Monica -, 1969-1970 1972. (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous sports through Game file. (Box 80)
  - Papers - residents through Population history. (Box 81)
  - Population sheets - through Media list -, 1966-1968 1967. (Box 82)
  - Press releases through Joe Galata - chron file. (Box 83)
  - Joe Galata - Chronological through 1967 Conference Meeting., July 30 to September December 1969 (Box 84)
  - First regents' conference through Reno. (Box 85)
  - Reno - Frank Lago - Correspondence - through San Bruno Jail Project., 1965-1966 (Box 86)
  - San Diego - through San Francisco -, 1962-1965 1968-1969. (Box 87)
  - Sorkin, Dan - Deposition theatre through SM - negative of store front. (Box 88)
  - SM - correspondence - through SM - miscellaneous., 1960 (Box 89)
  - Santa Monica - photos through SM - director's correspondence - John Coons -, 1972. (Box 90)
  - SM - correspondence - 1-3 / through Final report on Patton State Hospital project -, 1972 1977. (Box 91)
  - Santa Monica city council fight through James S. Coleman - article -, 1972. (Box 92)
  - Rod Mullen, director of education - through Photos - New York -, 1973 1978. (Box 93)
  - Subject files - SCRAM through Facts & figures re Synanon services / general info - by Steve Simon. (Box 94)
  - Sponsors of Synanon - through Stew - heretics - Ron Eschenauer -, 1961 1974. (Box 95)
  - Stew - Synanonites - Pete Buonaiuto - through Stew - daily events -, 1974 November 1975. (Box 96)
  - Stew - daily events - through Stew - the mobile Stew -, December 1975 1976. (Box 97)
  - Stew - Synanon design - through Stew scheduling -, 1976 1978. (Box 98)
  - Stew filing - through Stockholders report -, 1978 1966. (Box 99)
  - Stockholders report - through Synanon - 10 & 15 year anniversary., 1968 (Box 100)
  - Synanon church - Arizona through Screenplay - Synanon House - by S. Lee Pogostin -, 1963. (Box 101)
  - Screenplay - Synanon - 1st estimating draft - through Synanon - Second Street market - literature., 1964 (Box 102)
  - Synanon songbook through Tomales Bay correspondence - foreign. (Box 103)
  - Weekly reports from Tomales Bay - through Transportation, July-August 1965 1969. (Box 104)
  - United Farm Workers through A Synanon love match. (Box 105)
  - Westport - daily reports through Women -, 1964. (Box 106)
  - Newspaper articles - through Bulletin boards -, 1959-1966 May 1973. (Box 107)
  - Women - through Cigarrette hustle / no somoking letters., 1965-1967 (Box 107)
- Synanon Events and Interviews - Reels and Cassettes
  - n.d. (Box 603)
  - n.d. (Box 604)
  - 1956, 1961, 1963-64. (Box 605)
  - 1962. (Box 606)
  - 1963. (Box 607)
  - [See box 605 for 1964]., 1965 (Box 608)
  - 1965. (Box 609)
  - 1965. (Box 610)
  - 1966. (Box 611)
  - 1966. (Box 612)
  - 1966. (Box 613)
  - 1966. (Box 614)
  - 1967. (Box 615)
  - 1967. (Box 616)
  - 1967-1968. (Box 617)
  - 1968. (Box 618)
  - 1968. (Box 619)
  - 1968. (Box 620)
  - 1968. (Box 621)
  - 1968. (Box 622)
  - 1968. (Box 623)
  - 1969. (Box 624)
  - 1969. (Box 625)
  - 1969. (Box 626)
  - 1969. (Box 627)
  - 1969. (Box 628)
  - 1969-1970. (Box 629)
  - 1970. (Box 630, Box 631, Box 632, Box 633, Box 634, Box 635)
  - 1971. (Box 636, Box 637, Box 638, Box 639, Box 640, Box 641, Box 642, Box 643, Box 644)
  - 1972. (Box 645, Box 646, Box 647, Box 648, Box 649, Box 650, Box 651, Box 652, Box 653, Box 654, Box 655, Box 656, Box 657)
  - 1973. (Box 658, Box 659, Box 660, Box 661, Box 662, Box 663, Box 664, Box 665, Box 666)
  - 1974. (Box 667, Box 668, Box 669, Box 670, Box 671, Box 672, Box 673, Box 674, Box 675)
  - 1975. (Box 676, Box 677, Box 678, Box 679, Box 680, Box 681, Box 682, Box 683, Box 684, Box 685, Box 686, Box 687)
  - 1976. (Box 688, Box 689, Box 690, Box 691, Box 692, Box 693, Box 694, Box 695, Box 696, Box 697)
  - 1977. (Box 698, Box 699, Box 700, Box 701, Box 702, Box 703, Box 704)
  - 1978. (Box 705, Box 706, Box 707, Box 708, Box 709, Box 710, Box 711)
  - 1979. (Box 712)
  - 1980. (Box 713)
  - 1980-1987. (Box 714)
- Synanon Impact Study
  - Impact study listings of materials checked out to law office through IBI 7. (Box 184)
  - IBI 8 through IBI 18. (Box 185)
  - IBI 19 through IBI 24. (Box 186)
  - IBI 25 through IBI 28. (Box 187)
  - IBI 29 through IBI 39. (Box 188)
  - IBI 40 through IBI 49. (Box 189)
  - IBI 50 (1 of 2) through IBI 58. (Box 190)
  - IBI 60 through IBI 73. (Box 191)
  - IBI 74 through IBI 89. (Box 192)
  - IBI 90 through IBI 102. (Box 193)
  - IBI 103 through IBI 116. (Box 194)
  - IBI 117 through IBI 136. (Box 195)
  - IBI 137 through IBI 162. (Box 196)
  - IBI 164 through IBI 175. (Box 197)
  - IBI 177 through IBI 186. (Box 198)
  - IBI 187 through IBI 192. (Box 199)
  - IBI 193 through IBI 213. (Box 200)
  - IBI 214 through IBI 243. (Box 201)
  - IBI 244 through IBI 258. (Box 202)
- Synanon Music and Musicians
  - Reel to reel tapes. (Box 601)
  - Reel to reel tapes. (Box 602)
- Synanon Scene
  - August 1967-September 1968. (Box 59)
- Transcripts
  - Fight, flight or put your head in the sand - STVSC lecture through Operation By-Pass, November 7-24, 1965 June 10-11, 1965. (Box 176)
  - CED on addiction through SF Examiner libel suit. (Box 177)
  - Steve Simon interviews CED on Game - through Steve Simon interviews CED on Synanon -, July 31, 1974 July 31, 1974. (Box 179)
  - Life article - through SFVSC 17 - role or not -, January 31, 1969 April 12, 1966. (Box 178)
  - Synanon Stylist (used in court case) through Ebony magazine. (Box 323)
  - IBI 259 through IBI 263. (Box 262)
  - IBI 265 through IBI 278. (Box 263)
  - IBI 279 through IBI 302. (Box 264)
  - IBI 303 through Paper - how to become a synanon fanatic. (Box 265)
  - Transcript - ladies in repose through Synanon philosophy. (Box 266)
  - Synanon - an educational society through Time / Life special report, 1965. (Box 267)
  - Time complaint through UC Berkeley. (Box 268)
  - Valley voice through Westport News - Dodd, July 9, 1964. (Box 269)
  - Synanon - Westport battles through Word on water for TB, the, 1963 1973. (Box 270)
  - Yablonsky - CED on LSD through Synanon education / pamphlets. (Box 271)
  - Synanon game by Steve Simon through Transcript - Unicept. (Box 272)
  - Tape logging through Bite-size. (Box 273)
  - Movie company through Synanon distribution network. (Box 274)
  - TB miscellaneous through Unicept syllabus and drill information., 1967-1968 (Box 275)
- Video Tapes (1-inch cassettes)
  - 8 cassettes., 1976-1978 (Box 391)
  - 14 cassettes., 1973-1978 (Box 392)
  - 14 cassettes., 1973-1983 (Box 393)
  - 14 cassettes., 1976-1982 (Box 394)
  - 14 cassettes., 1974-1979 (Box 395)
  - 14 cassettes., 1974-1980 (Box 396)
  - 14 cassettes., 1976-1983 (Box 397)
  - 14 cassettes., 1975-1983 (Box 398)
  - 14 cassettes., 1974-1985 (Box 399)
  - 14 cassettes., 1975-1983 (Box 400)
  - 5 cassettes., 1976-1979 (Box 401)
- Video Tapes - Small Reel to Reel
  - 26 reels., 1975-1979 (Box 383)
  - 26 reels., 1975-1981 (Box 384)
  - 26 reels., 1975-1983 (Box 385)
  - 26 reels., 1974-1983 (Box 386)
  - 26 reels., 1973-1977 (Box 387)
  - 26 reels., 1973-1981 (Box 388)
  - 26 reels., 1973-1982 (Box 389)
  - 26 reels., 1972-1978 (Box 390)
  - 13 reels., 1974-1977 (Box 391)
- Video Tapes - U-matic(s)
  CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - 12 U-matics, 1977-1983 (Box 406)
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
  - 18 U-matics, 1979-1983 (Box 407)
  - 4 U-matics, 1974, 1978, 1982, undated (Box 408)
- Video Tapes - BETA
  - 22 tapes, 1963-1983 (Box 405)
  - 8 Betamaxes, 1963-1984 (Box 406)
- Video Tapes - Large Reel-to-Reel
  - 10 reels, 1975-1976 (Box 401)
  - 18 reels, 1974-1981 (Box 402)
  - 19 reels., 1974-1980 (Box 403)
  - 19 reels., 1974-1977 (Box 404)
  - 7 reels., 1973-1977 (Box 405)
- Video Tapes - Miscellaneous Sized Tapes
  - 3 items., n.d. (Box 409)
- Writing Research Files
  - Act as if through By - pass series edited copies kick-off meeting, February 1965. (Box 208)
  - By-pass book proposal intro and selected essays through CED holds court project - savings of photos of CED. (Box 209)
  - CED holds court project - saving of Goldworm proof sheets through Confusion. (Box 210)
  - Cube through The game book chapters. (Box 211)
  - The game - interviews #1 through HBJ proposal - being and becoming 2nd draft. (Box 212)
  - HBJ proposal - CED talks about space-time through HBJ research proposal. (Box 213)
  - HBJ proposal - protection copies through Bathing at the Home Place. (Box 214)
  - Breaking away from the Synanon community through JHP article working papers file #3. (Box 215)
  - JHP article - working papers file #4 through Transcript - gettiong acquainted - town place game -, July 7, 1977. (Box 216)
  - CED talks about marriage (essay) - first draft through Feedback. (Box 217)
  - Playback school through CED quotes produced in ABC case from Mike Kaiser file. (Box 218)
  - Betty D quotes - compiled by Nancy Mason through Religion - research material. (Box 219)
  - Superior Court of California - declaration of C Mason Hervey through SS research files - speaking engagements. (Box 220)
  - Stapleton scrapbook - photos through Synanon history. (Box 221)
  - Synanon timeline through Transcript - thickened light (copy) -, July 2, 1968. (Box 222)
  - Thickened light - demonstrator's notes through Washington brochure - 2d draft. (Box 223)
- Video Tapes - VHS(s)
  - 1 VHS, 1983 (Box 406)